Michael Ayodele Bamidele

mbamidele29@gmail.com (+234) 8133999175 No 27, Elephant Estate Oluyole Ibadan, Oyo

Summary

Enthusiastic software engineer with over 4 years experience participating in the complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched applications while having proficient skills in technologies which includes Php (Laravel), Java (Android development), JavaSpring, NodeJs, ReactJs, C#, Python, Flutter. Vast experience in Windows Server Management and database analysis and design with Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL and PostgreSQL databases. Skilled in analytical thinking, creative problem solving, agile development processes and in creation and integration of APIs. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

Education

Federal University Oye-Ekiti

Computer Science (B. Sc.) • Ekiti 09/2017 Second Class - 4.02 CGPA

Oladipo Alayande School Of Science

SSCE • Ibadan, Oyo 09/2011

Baptist Secondary School

JSCE · Ibadan, Oyo 09/2018

Glorious International Nursery and Primary School

• Ibadan, Oyo 09/2005

Skills

- PHP
- Python
- Flutter
- JQuery
- Database Development
- MySQL
- HTML
- Organizational skills
- PostgreSQL

- NodeJS
- Java
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- MS SSMS (Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio)
- CSS
- XML (Extensible Markup Language)
- Customer service

Experience

Boca Konsult Global Services Limited

Software Engineer • Lagos, Lagos

02/2018 - Present

- Development and deployment of android applications using Java and XML.
- Development and deployment of mobile applications using Flutter.

- Development and deployment of Websites
- Maintenance of deployed applications
- Optimised existing applications to increase performance
- Integration of APIs and payment gateways
- · Management of Windows Server
- Provision of customer service support and trainings to end users.

Distance Learning Centre University of Ibadan Idi-Ose

Web Developer Intern • Ibadan, Oyo

08/2015 - 01/2016

- Development of websites using wordpress
- Network and database management
- Develop UIs with JSP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- IT Support Staff

Treasure Foundation Kiddies College, Oke Ado

Teacher • Ibadan, Oyo

08/2011 - 12/2013

- Create detailed lesson plans based on students' current knowledge and state requirements
- Address any student behavioural problems, calming disruptive students and escalating to principal as needed
- Communicated clearly with parents and teacher to fully understand student needs
- Present fun and instructional lessons that encourage student participation

Project Experience

- Development of KVG mobile app for electricity, satellite tv and Telecom vending for kallakpower.com.
- Development of android app for BOCA Konsult for network related issues. i.e MTN, GLO, AIRTEL, 9MOBILE.
- Development of Meter Manager Application for Adroit.
- Development of an inventory system for meter management for IBEDC.
- Development of a meter purchase system for IBEDC.
- Development of a field operations application for IBEDC.
- Development of an electricity purchase application for Top Energy.
- Maintenance of Windows server.
- SQL query optimisation.
- Maintenance of existing websites and mobile applications.

Languages

· English

Yoruba

Reference

Agu Caleb

Boca Konsult Global Services Limited.

(+234) 7035759270